# **Lauren Leodore**

## **Coatings Production Engineer - Biocoat, Inc**

Oaklyn, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Lauren-Leodore/0edb2e031739fab4

Management level employee with diversified manufacturing experience in high and low volume production with an extensive background in manufacturing and chemical engineering. Demonstrated success in introducing new products into production, and in developing, implementing and managing new processes to improve quality and productivity. Hands-on experience in fabrication, machining, assembly and lean manufacturing. Creative analytical problem solver with excellent team-building skills.

**Technical Ability** 

- \* Delta V
- \* Minitab
- \* SAP
- \* ISO 9000 & 9001
- \* Statistics for Manufacturing (Six Sigma)
- \* Trained Hot Work and Confined Space Coordinator
- \* Lean Manufacturing
- \* Ergonomic Assessments
- \* Process Set-Up
- \* Plant Scale-Up
- \* Process Improvement
- \* Allen Bradley PLC5 Programming

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Coatings Production Engineer**

Biocoat, Inc - Horsham, PA - May 2014 to Present

Successfully implemented Delta V automation software to reduce operator variability when running reactors. The addition of engineering controls reduced the risk for out of specification batches; therefore, keeping production on schedule.

- \* Developed reactor cleaning method in order to utilize multiple reactors for different products without risk of product contamination.
- \* Decreased batch analysis time by 2 hours by introducing a microwave moisture analyzer to determine solids contents in all coatings products.
- \* Designed and implemented a dual shaft high shear agitation impeller to decrease batch mixing time by 12 hours; therefore, increasing productivity.
- \* Reduced use of process water by implementing the use of a recirculating chiller unit to cool reactors.
- \* Project lead in reactor scale-up project. Successfully designed and calculated heat transfer requirements for a 50L reactor.
- \* Interfaced with several contractors and assisted in building design meetings for a new production facility.
- \* Developed chemical waste procedure to comply with OSHA regulations
- \* Excellent process validation skills
- \* Trained operators on all new equipment
- \* Fill-in supervisor as needed

## **Process Engineer II**

Ashland, Inc - Philadelphia, PA - March 2013 to May 2014

Championed a capital project to replace existing inhibitor dispensing pumps with air diaphragm pumps to reduce chance of injury and improve ease of operation.

- \* Successfully worked with production supervisors/operators to achieve over 100 days without a late shipment.
- \* Developed method for loading tankwagons that meet customer specifications without requiring lab adjustments.
- \* Member of ergonomic assessment team that meets quarterly and focuses on processes that score high on BRIEF/BEST forms.
- \* Track batch cycle times and identify points of loss and correct to prevent production downtime.
- \* Investigate all off spec and late shipments and identify root causes and corrective actions.
- \* Assist in annual production shutdown by participating in lock-out/tag-out and administering hot work and confined space entry permits.
- \* Audit chemical waste area and inspected waste drums weekly. All out of compliance waste drums were corrected by the end of shift.
- \* Member of plant management team with active involvement in weekly leadership meetings where plant improvement initiatives were discussed.
- \* Back-up production supervisor (nightshift and weekends included)

## **Process Engineer**

Johnson Matthey - West Deptford, NJ - June 2008 to March 2013

Identify process improvements to improve yields and/or lower production costs, enhancing the overall efficiency and cost effectiveness of plant operations.

- \* Provide engineering support and process, mechanical, and instrumentation troubleshooting necessary to meet all production/customer requirements.
- \* Actively participate in Lean Manufacturing Initiatives such as A3 investigations and 5S implementations.
- \* Strong ability to identify where a process requires standardization via statistical analysis and in order to improve plant processes.
- \* Oversee the activities of four chemical operators in order to ensure that training of newly installed processes is executed successfully and that new equipment is running smoothly.
- \* Supervise production when needed

#### Refining Technical Specialist

- \* Aided internal refinery in engineering a metal scavenging flow column which recovers 30TO metal per month.
- \* Present at customer sites (both internally and externally) throughout North America to educate both Pharmaceutical and Manufacturing facilities about the benefits of implementing metal scavengers
- \* Screen both internal and external product/waste streams to help engineer the best plant sized scavenging set-up and to show customers how much metal they are losing each year in TO and dollars
- \* Travel to customer sites and supervise equipment installation while instructing operators how to use scavengers properly for optimum performance
- \* Supervise two on-site chemical operators to ensure that internal scavenging column is properly functioning

## **EDUCATION**

## M.S. in Biomaterials and Tissue Engineering

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA 2004 to 2006

## **B.S.** in Biological Sciences

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA 2000 to 2004